Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project collection 1980-1983
AFC 2017/035
Posen, I. Sheldon; Miska, Maxine
5310 items received in; 21 containers; 7 linear feet.
15 linear in.
500 documents.
6 sound tape reels: analog; 7 in.
3 sound cassettes: analog.
984 photographs: film, negatives, black and white.
61 photographs: film, negatives, color.
169 photographic prints: black and white; various sizes.
23 photographic prints; color; various sizes.
approximately 3588 slides: color; 35 mm.
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Fieldwork for the Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project undertaken and coordinated by Sheldon Posen and Maxine Miska, 1980-1983. The project surveyed and recorded traditions in Brooklyn, New York, on behalf of the Brooklyn Educational and Cultural Alliance (BECA) documenting ethnic foodways, neighborhood events, private celebrations, street life and play, store fronts, music, folk theater, religious events, urban sports and pastimes. Ethnic groups include African Americans, diasporic Jews (including Hassidic), Greek Americans, Italian Americans, Polish Americans, Puerto Ricans, West Indian Americans, Irish Americans, Chinese Americans, and Ukrainian Americans. The annual West Indian Carnival in Prospect Park/Eastern Parkway was documented in-depth. Joseph Sciorra and Sheldon Posen documented the Our Lady of Mount Carmel giglio tradition with photographs by Martha Cooper. Sheldon Posen also photographed the dancing of the giglio in New Jersey. The collection includes photographs of Greek Easter celebrations, Sukkot and Etrog Market, and documentation of exhibitions about Brooklyn folklife.
Provenance
Ira Sheldon Posen; Donation; 2017, 2018.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research; access to collection materials may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Scope and Content
Fieldwork for the Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project undertaken and coordinated by Sheldon Posen and Maxine Miska, 1980-1983. The project surveyed and recorded traditions in Brooklyn, New York, on behalf of the Brooklyn Educational and Cultural Alliance (BECA) documenting ethnic foodways, neighborhood events, private celebrations, street life and play, store fronts, music, folk theater, religious events, urban sports and pastimes. Ethnic groups include African Americans, diasporic Jews (including Hassidic), Greek Americans, Italian Americans, Polish Americans, Puerto Ricans, West Indian Americans, Irish Americans, Chinese Americans, and Ukrainian Americans. The annual West Indian Carnival in Prospect Park/Eastern Parkway was documented in-depth. Joseph Sciorra and Sheldon Posen documented the Our Lady of Mount Carmel giglio tradition with photographs by Martha Cooper. Sheldon Posen also photographed the dancing of the giglio in New Jersey. The collection includes photographs of Greek Easter celebrations, Sukkot and Etrog Market, and documentation of exhibitions about Brooklyn folklife.
Arrangement
The Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project collection is organized in 5 series:
Series 1: Giglio, Italian American traditions, 1980-1983
Series 2: Jewish traditions, 1981-1983
Series 3: West Indian American traditions, 1980-1983
Series 4: Brooklyn community traditions, 1980-1983
Series 5: Folklife Study related materials, 1980-1983
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Cooper, Martha; Miska, Maxine; Posen, I. Sheldon; Sciorra, Joseph
Organizations
Brooklyn Educational & Cultural Alliance; Manteo Sicilian Marionette Theatre.; West Indian American Day Carnival Association.; West Indian American Day Carnival Parade (Brooklyn, N.Y.)
Subjects
African American quiltmakers--New York (State)--New York.; African Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Caribbean Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Chinese Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Christmas--1980-1990--New York (State)--New York.; Costumes--1980-1990--New York (State)--New York.; Easter eggs--1980-1990--New York (State)--New York.; Easter--New York (State)--New York.; Epiphany--New York (State)--New York.; Festivals--New York (State)--New York.; Folk music--Puerto Rico.; Folklore--New York (State)--New York.; Greek Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Hasidim--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Irish Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Italian American Catholics--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Italian Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Jewish marriage customs and rites--New York (State)--New York--Photographs.; Jews--New York (State)--New York--Religious life.; Parades--1980-1990--New York (State)--New York.; Parades--New York (State)--New York.; Polish Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Puerto Ricans--Music.; Puerto Ricans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Puppets--1980-1990--New York (State)--New York.; Purim--New York (State)--New York.; Religious festivals--New York (State)--New York.; Sicilian Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Sukkot--New York (State)--New York.; Ukrainian Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Weddings--1980-1990--New York (State)--New York.; West Indian Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.
Places
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
Titles
Brooklyn Educational and Cultural Alliance (BECA) Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project
Form/Genre
Aerial photographs.; Correspondence.; Documentary photographs.; Field notes.; Interviews.; Oral histories.; Photographs--Color--1980-1990.; Sound recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Giglio, Italian American traditions, 1980-1983
  Manuscripts and photographs documenting the Giglio Feast, a religious festival and street fair. The Giglio Feast usually opens the week after the 4th of July, and runs for 12 days including the feast day of Our Lady of Mount Carmel on July 16th, in Williamsburg, Brooklyn. The feast pays homage to the patron saint, San Paolino or Saint Paulinus, of Nola, Italy, and culminates with dancing the giglio, a huge flower-laden steeple of wood, more than 80 feet in height, carried through the streets on the shoulders of hundreds of men. Field work by Sheldon Posen, Maxine Miska, Joseph Sciorra, and Martha Cooper.
  - Giglio field notes (folder 1), 1981, manuscripts (Box-folder 1/1)
    Joe Sciorra field notes about the Giglio Feast. Includes index cards with locations and neighborhoods.
  - Giglio field notes (folder 2), 1981, manuscripts; 5 black-and-white contact sheets (Box-folder 1/2)
    Includes planning field notes, program for 93rd Annual Feast of Our Lady of Mount Carmel and Saint Paulinus, and contact sheets 180-1, 180-3, 180-4, 18186-2, 18186-3.
  - Giglio research, 1981-1982, manuscripts; 1 black-and-white photographic print (Box-folder 1/3)
    Includes "Notes for Elliot Willensky, 1982 (for exhibit)," which includes notes about the hierarchy, participants, and roles of Giglio.
  - Giglio research, 1982, manuscripts; 23 color photographic prints (Box-folder 1/4)
    Includes planning field notes, notes about Sheldon Posen and Joseph Sciorra article/book, and articles, programs for 93rd Annual Feast of Our Lady of Mount Carmel and Saint Paulinus. Includes 23 color photographs of the Giglio procession.
  - Library research, 1982-1985, manuscripts (Box-folder 1/5)
    Correspondence, handwritten notes, photocopies of articles and book chapters about the festival in honor of Saint Paulinus/Giglio Feast in Nola, Italy, and in Brooklyn.
  - Research, 1983, manuscripts (Box-folder 1/6)
    Correpondence, handwritten notes, poem, and program for 95th Annual Feast of Our Lady of Mount Carmel and Saint Paulinus.
  - Giglio, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 6/03)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Mostly originals.
  - Giglio, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 9/17)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper. Originals and duplicates.
  - Giglio, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 9/18-10/18)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Scenes from the neighborhood surrounding the Giglio Feast event. Mostly duplicates. 18 color negatives (35mm) were relocated to Box 5, Folder 2.
  - Giglio, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 10/20)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Mostly duplicates.
  - Giglio, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 10/21)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Mixed content. Originals and duplicates.
  - Giglio, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/28-12/28)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Originals and duplicates.
  - Giglio, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 12/30)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper. Originals.
  - Giglio, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 12/31)
  - Giglio, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/34)
  - Giglio, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/35)
  - Giglio, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/36)
  - Giglio, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/38)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper (and possibly also, Sheldon Posen). Originals.
  - Giglio, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/41)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Mostly originals.
  - Giglio, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/42)
  - Giglio, 1982-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 15/46)
  - Giglio, 1981-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 15/48-17/48)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Originals and duplicates. Mixed content. Mostly for Brooklyn Folklife presentation.
  - Giglio, 1981-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 17/49-20/49)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Mostly originals. Mixed content.
  - Giglio, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 20/52-21/52)
  - Giglio, 1980-1984, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/55)
    Some photographs likely by Sheldon Posen; others are captures of historical photographs of Giglio Feast, church, and families.
  - Giglio, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/57)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Originals.
  - Giglio, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/59)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen.
  - Giglio and church, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/44)
  - Bronx Giglio, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/24)
  - Old Giglio, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/25)
    Color photographs of black-and-white photographs from older Giglio events.
  - New Jersey Giglio, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/26)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen. Mostly originals.
  - Questionnaire, 1981-1982, manuscripts (Box-folder 1/10)
    Questionnaire for participants of the Feast of St. Paulinus and the Giglio.
  - Slide show, 1981-1984, manuscripts (Box-folder 1/11)
    Paper titled, "'It's in the Blood:' Dancing the Giglio in Brooklyn," with edits, notes, and correspondence.
  - Miscellaneous, 1983-1984, manuscripts; 3 black-and-white photographic prints (8x10) (Box-folder 2/1)
    Research notes, correspondence, newspaper clippings, pamphlet from Giglio exhibit at the Brooklyn Historical Society, and still images relating to the Giglio. 3 35mm color slides were relocated to Box 21/61(numbered 61_001, 61_002, 61_003), 2 black-and-white copy negatives (35mm) and 6 black-and-white negatives (35mm) were relocated to Box 4, Folder 1, and 6 color negatives (35mm) were relocated to Box 5, Folder 1.
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1980s, 37 color negatives (35mm) (Box-folder 5/3)
    Unidentified scenes from the Giglio festival. Photographer is unknown. Roll number: A059910. See also Box 5.
- Series 2: Jewish traditions, 1981-1983
  Manuscripts, photographs, and sound recordings about Jewish, specifically Hasidic, holidays and traditions. Includes documentation of a Hasidic Lubavitcher (movement of Hasidic Judaism) wedding, as well as materials about the Sukkot, Purim, and Passover holidays.
  - Matza making, 1981-1983, manuscripts; 58 black-and-white photographic prints (Box-folder 2/2)
    Black-and-white photographic prints by Martha Cooper and "The Worlds of Brooklyn Matza Making," an edited paper by Sheldon Posen about matza making foodways traditions. Includes notes and script of play about matza making.
  - Brooklyn Matza making, 1981-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 8/12-9/12)
  - Hasidic Lubavitcher wedding I, 1981-1982, manuscripts; 69 black-and-white photographic prints; 18 black-and-white contact sheets. (Box-folder 2/3-4)
    Includes Hasidic (Lubavitch) wedding invitation and prayer book from wedding, as well as a story board about a Hasidic wedding. Black-and-white photographic prints and negatives of a Hasidic wedding, including images of the Kabbalat Panim (greeting of the bride and groom), the Chupah (canopy), and dancing. Contact sheet roll numbers 21042-1-21042-11; 21058-1-21057-7. 612 black-and-white negatives (35mm) were relocated to Box 4, Folder 2: roll numbers 21042-1-21042-11; 21058-1-21057-7.
  - Hasidic Lubavitcher wedding II, 1982, manuscripts; 16 black-and-white phographic prints; 10 contact sheets. (Box-folder 2/5)
    Photographs of women taken by Martha Cooper; photographs of men taken by Sheldon Posen. Contact sheet roll numbers 21139-2, 21139-4, 21139-6, 21139-7, 21139-8; 21042-3, 21042-5; 21160-1, 21160-3, 21160-4. 274 black-and-white negatives (35mm) were relocated to Box 4, Folder 3: roll numbers 21139-2, 21139-4, 21139-6, 21139-7, 21139-8; 21160-1, 21160-3, 21160-4.
  - Hasidic wedding conversation I, 1982, 1 cassette tape (Item-id AFC 2017/035: SR008)
    Hassidic wedding conversation, tape 1. Conversation with Mordechai and Tsivia. MBRS shelf number: RYQ 2409
  - Hasidic wedding conversation II, 1982, 1 cassette tape (Item-id SR009)
    Hassidic wedding conversation, tape 2. Conversation with Mordechai and Tsivia. MBRS shelf number: RYQ 2410
  - Hasids and chickens, 1981-1983, 21 black-and-white photographic prints; 4 black-and-white contact sheets. (Box-folder 2/6)
    Photographic material by Martha Cooper of kapparot ceremony, ritual between Rosh Hashana and Yom Kippur to transfer a person's sins to a chicken. Contact sheet roll numbers 17195-1, 17195-2, 17195-3; 17272. 90 black-and-white negatives (35mm) were relocated to Box 4, Folder 4: roll numbers 17195-1, 17195-2, 17195-3; 5826-3.
  - Sukkot, Essex Street Market, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 6/01)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Photographs of the Essex Street Market in preparation for the Sukkot holiday. Includes documentation of a Hasidic Lubavitcher wedding, as well as materials about Sukkot, Purim, and Passover.
  - Sukkot, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/23)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Originals and duplicates.
  - Sukkot, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/28-12/28)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Originals and duplicates. Mixed content.
  - Sukkot, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 12/33-13/33)
  - Sukkot, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/36)
  - Sukkot, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/40)
  - Sukkot, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/45-15/45)
  - Sukkot, 1981-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 15/47)
  - Sukkot, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 20/50)
  - Sukkot, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/53)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Images from a market selling Lulav and Etrog (likely Essex Street Market), two of the Four Species used during the Jewish holiday of Sukkot.
  - Sukkot and tabernacle, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 12/29)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Mostly duplicates. Sukkot traditions and an ornate Jewish temple (tabernacle).
  - Purim, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 7/06)
  - Purim, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/58)
  - Hebrew writing, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 10/22-11/22)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Ushpizin.
  - Hasidic content, 1980-1981, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/39-14/39)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper. Mixed content.
  - Hasidic content, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/43)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper and Sheldon Posen. Mixed content.
- Series 3: West Indian American traditions, 1980-1983
  Manuscript and photographs relating to the West Indian Day Parade, or, Carnival, (organized by the West Indian American Day Carnival Association), an annual celebration held on American Labor Day that celebrates the history, culture, music, food, and people from Caribbean countries.
  - Brooklyn Carnival research, 1980-1983, manuscripts (Box-folder 2/7)
    Notes, articles, program books, exhibit guide, writings, research, and correspondence related to the West Indian-American Carnival.
  - Carnival lights, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 6/05)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper of the West Indian Carnival.
  - West Indian Carnival, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 9/16)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Photographs of music, dance, and costume construction.
  - West Indian Carnival, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 10/19)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen.
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 10/21)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Mixed content.
  - Costume making, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 10/22-11/22)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper.
  - West Indian Carnival, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/23)
  - West Indian Carnival, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 11/27)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Photographs of ornate costumes, steel drum ensemble (Sonics steel orchestra), and events honoring Bob Marley.
  - West Indian Carnival, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 12/29)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Ornate costumes and steel drum ensemble.
  - West Indian Carnival, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 12/32)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Constructing ornate costumes, decorations for parade.
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 12/33-13/33)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. West Indian American Day Carnival Association (WIADCA) festival with indoor and outdoor stage, ornate decorations, and steel drum ensemble.
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/38)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper (and possibly also, Sheldon Posen). Ornate costumes and dance with accordion.
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/40)
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/43)
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/45-15/45)
    Photographs likely by Sheldon Posen. Costume making for West Indian American Day Carnival Association (WIADCA) festival (West Indian Day Parade).
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1981-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 15/47)
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1981-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 15/48-17/48)
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1981-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 17/49-20/49)
  - West Indian Day Parade, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/56)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper. Costume making, parade, steel drums.
  - West Indian content, 1980-1981, 35mm color slides (Box-group 13/39-14/39)
- Series 4: Brooklyn community traditions, 1980-1983
  Manuscripts, photographs, and sound recordings about a range of communities and immigrant traditions in Brooklyn, such as that of Ukrainians, Greeks, Chinese, Irish, and Puerto Rico. Includes documentation of exhibits that Posen, Sciorra, and Cooper put together, as well as material relating to Brooklyn business establishments.
  - Ukrainian Christmas, 1982, manuscripts (Box-folder 2/8)
    Field notes documenting Ukrainian Christmas traditions of the Savchak family, including foodways and gift giving.
  - Greek Easter, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/60)
    Photographs likely be Sheldon Posen. Originals. Photographs of Greek Easter, or Christo Anesti.
  - Afro-American quilting, February, 1982, manuscripts (Box-folder 2/9)
    Field notes and descriptions of interviews about African American quilts and children's games. Fieldworker, Deborah Finley-Jackson.
  - Chinese, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 7/08)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen. Qingming festival.
  - Irish Clann Éireann, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 8/10)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Originals and duplicates. Mixed content (includes Giglio, Purim, Easter, Candy Store, Chruszik, Irish Pipe Band).
  - Irish content, 1980-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 14/43)
  - Irish content, 1981-1982, 35mm color slides (Box-group 21/56)
    Photographs by Martha Cooper.
  - Polish, Easter eggs, Chruscik, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 8/11)
    Mostly or all originals. Easter egg painting and baking chruscik.
  - Puerto Rican music, session 1, February, 1982, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2017/035: SR001)
    Musicians: Sergio Ortiz (vocal), Jose Rivera (cuatro), Ismael Natel (guitar), Diego Diaz (quirro), Genaro Cruz (conga), Maria Ortiz (coro, vocal).
  - Puerto Rican music, session 2, February, 1982, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2017/035: SR002)
    Musicians: Sergio Ortiz (vocal), Jose Rivera (cuatro), Ismael Natel (guitar), Diego Diaz (quirro, maracas), Genaro Cruz (conga), Maria Ortiz (vocal), Benjamin Soto (guiro, coro).
  - Puerto Rican music, session 3, February, 1982, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2017/035: SR003)
    Musicians: Sergio Ortiz (vocal), Jose Rivera (cuatro), Ismael Natel (guitar), Diego Diaz (quirro), Genaro Cruz (conga).
  - Puerto Rican, 3 kings, part 1, February, 1982, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2017/035: SR004)
    Part 1. St. Michael's.
  - Puerto Rican, 3 kings, part 2, February, 1982, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2017/035: SR005)
    Part 2. St. Michael's.
  - Puerto Rican "kitchen music," February, 1982, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2017/035: SR006)
    Musicians: Sergio Ortiz (vocal, guitar), Maria Ortiz (vocal), Benjamin Soto (guirro).
  - Puerto Rican, Jibaro music, February, 1982, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2017/035: SR007)
    Sergio Ortiz and band.
  - Miscellaneous Brooklyn slides, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 6/02)
    Photographs mostly by Martha Cooper.
  - Miscellaneous Brooklyn slides, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 6/04)
  - Miscellaneous Brooklyn slides, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 6/05-7/05)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen and Martha Cooper. Mixed content.
  - Candy store; Bay Ridge, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 7/07)
    Photographs by Shedon Posen; all or mostly originals.
  - Aerials: Brooklyn, Manhattan, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 7/09-8/09)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen. Aerial views of Brooklyn and Manhattan.
  - Stick ball, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 9/13)
    Photographs by Sheldon Posen. Mostly or all originals.
  - Store fronts; Ukrainian Christmas, 1980-1983, 35mm color slides (Box-group 9/14)